Lucas Padilha dos Santos

Sheffield - England

Full Stack Web Developer

E-mail: lucas@padilha.dev

Linkedin: lucaspadilhadossantos

Github: LucasPadilha
Facebook: Padilhaght
Website: https://padilha.dev

Summary

Over 10 years of experience in fullstack web development. Of these, over 4 years also include team leadership.

I have an Associate's Degree in Internet Systems (graduated in 2017) by Universidade do Vale do Itajaí.

Since 2022 I've been working as Principal Full Stack Developer at one of the leading pharmaceutical agencies in the world, working accross multiple projects with people across multiple countries.

Previously, worked as Lead Developer at one of the leading educational companies in the UK. Mainly leading the development, maintaining the legacy apps and developing new features with stakeholders.

I've worked as development coordinator in large scale projects with global impact, coordinating a team of developers on the maintenance and development of new features for legacy software.

I've also worked as lead developer in the software development for a medical field startup, where I've been in charge of leading a team of developers in the process of modelling and development of a web platform and Android & iOS apps.

Past experiences include maintaining and feature development for an accounting ERP and development of responsive websites for a web agency.

Self-taught, creative and gamer in my spare time.

Abilities

Programming Languages

- PHP
 - Laravel
 - Drupal
 - Symfony
 - Slim
 - CodeIgniter
 - Wordpress
- Javascript
 - VueJS
 - React
 - Angular
 - Node
 - Electron
- JQuery
- Java
- PythonC#
- Project Standards

r roject otaniaarac

- Responsive Design
 - HTML5/CSS3Flex & Grid
 - Bootstrap
 - Bulma
 - TailwindCSS
- Model-View-Controller (MVC)
- Object Oriented Programming
- REST API / WebServices
- CI/CD

Databases

- MySQL
- MariaDB
- PostgreSQL

MongoDB

Others:

- Docker
- Cloud (Google Cloud, AWS, Digital Ocean)
- Version Control System
- UNIX (Linux & OSX)
- SEO
- Photoshop

Professional Experience

• 11/2022 to current - Principal Full Stack Developer @ Avalere Health (former Fishawack Health)

Acting as Principal Developer at one of the leading pharmaceutical agencies in the world, working accross multiple projects with people all around the world. Main stack: PHP (Drupal, Laravel Framework), Javascript, VueJS, Docker, Git, AWS, CI/CD, MySQL, PostgreSQL.

• 08/2021 to 10/2022 - Lead Developer @ The Skills Network

Working as Lead Developer at one of the leading educational companies in the UK, main focus on the development of new features for the legacy app, as well as development of a version 2 for said app, using up-to-date technologies and frameworks to improve and progress the cloud-based app. Also acting as a mentor for Jr and Mid developers on the team, helping them understand the stack and troubleshoot issues. Main stack: PHP (Vanilla and Laravel framework), Javascript, VueJS, jQuery, Docker, Git, PostgreSQL.

• 10/2020 to 07/2021 - PHP Developer @ Surge MedTech

Worked as PHP developer on a mobile compliance & EPRF cloud platform for high performance EMS and CCTS teams, acting closely with stakeholders to develop new features and maintain legacy apps. Main stack: PHP (Laravel framework), Javascript, Angular.js, Gatsby.js, Strapi, Docker, Git, CI/CD, MySQL.

• 02/2018 to 11/2019 - Development Coordinator @ GeoSapiens Technology and Information

I worked as a development coordinator, managing a team of programmers in the development and maintenance of large web systems. I worked on several projects over time, maintaining legacy software, as well as developing new software with current technologies. Among my duties were direct communication with customers, setting priorities and modeling features. Main technologies: PHP (Symfony framework), Javascript, Knockout.js, Node.js, Java, CSS, Docker, Git, Jenkins.

• 06/2017 to 02/2018 - Lead Developer @ All Doctors

I worked as a Lead Developer setting priorities, managing the development team and developing new features. During the time I led the team we developed all the components of the platform (Website, Administrative Platform, API and Mobile Application) from the beginning, we integrated several external services (Webservices and Payment Gateways) as well as adding several new features.

• 03/2016 to 06/2017 - Front-end Developer @ Quax Websites and Applications

I worked as a front-end developer in the development of websites and applications focused on user experience, responsiveness, SEO and API integration, as well as participation in business and development decision-making.

• 03/2015 to 02/2016 - PHP Developer @ PerfilWeb Information Technology

Worked as developer on a web based ERP for accounting professionals using PHP, Javascript and Relational databases (MySQL and PostgreSQL), while mantaining legacy softwares, fixing bugs and developing new features. Also participated on feature modeling and decision making about business and development.

Education

- Associate's Degree Internet Systems (UNIVALI)
- Certificate Javascript (TreinaWeb)
- Certificate Advanced level PHP MVC (TreinaWeb)
- Certificate SEO Search Engine Optimization (TreinaWeb)
- Certificate iMasters Certified Professional Javascript Design Patterns (iMasters)
- Prize 3rd place in the 1st Startup Weekend Balneário Camboriú